andertons.co.uk 2019-10-29

# Privacy Policy - Andertons Music Co.

**1\. What type of data do we collect?**

We collect personal information, such as your name, postal addresses, email address, phone number, purchase history and browsing behaviour. We store this information when you place an order with Andertons Music Co. or submit your data to us (using a web-form or a newsletter sign-up form).

**2\. Why do we collect your data?**

We use a customer engagement system that will allow us to communicate with our customers and users in a sophisticated manner. What this means for you is that we'll make better use of all the data we have about you to ensure that we only send you emails that are completely relevant to you. It also means we will be able to offer an advance 'personal shopper' style experience that uses a combination of data based on how you interact with the site (behavioural data) and PII (when you're logged in).

We've built the website in such a way that you can browse and enjoy most of the site without ever having to give us any information that could identify you as a specific person (in legal parlance that data is referred to as PII - and includes, but isn't limited to, email address, name etc).

However some of the more advanced features of the site (including buying things!) do require some PII. This includes providing us with adequate information to process payment and delivery of your orders or contact you following the completion of Contact Us, Price Match or Newsletter Sign Up forms.

**3\. How we use your data**

An example might be that if we can see you're spending a lot of time browsing a particular category we might email you with some helpful information such as a video or buyers guide relating to that category. Without this technology we would only have the option to hope people found buyers guides on their own, or send emails to everyone (that had chosen to receive our marketing emails) regardless of whether it would be of any relevance. This technology is provided by Emarsys.

**4\. Disclosure**

Because PII is particularly sensitive, we're also particularly careful about how it's used: we never, ever share or sell PII (or any data for that matter) to any other business. The only exceptions are third party partners named on this page. These are trusted partners that allow us to deliver a better shopping experience, and data is only shared with them to enable that.

**5\. Our trusted partners**

Our trusted partners each have their own privacy policies and terms and conditions. Andertons Music Co. has no control over these, and they may change over time. We will endeavour to monitor any such changes, and terminate our use of their services, should we deem their privacy policy to be in conflict with our own or in anyway a threat to your privacy.

Our partners are listed below:

  * **Emarsys** \- providing an email marketing platform and on-site product recommender widgets based on your browsing behaviour. This requires the use of cookies. See below for more about cookies. To read Emarsys’ privacy policy, [click here.](https://www.emarsys.com/en/privacy-policy/)
  * **IBM** \- the platform on which our site is built.
  * **DB-IP** \- Simply put DB-IP enables us to provide more relevant delivery information around the site based on your IP address.
  * **DTB** \- the development team who build and maintain our site.
  * **Facebook** \- We never share your personal information with Facebook, but your information may be used to profile you against your Facebook account. This in turn allows us to serve you with relevant advertising on Facebook based on your browsing and purchase history.
  * **Google** \- We do not share your personal information with Google, but your information may be used to profile you against your existing Google account. This in turn allows us to serve you with relevant advertising on Google’s sites based on your browsing and purchase history.
  * **Google Customer Reviews** \- After your purchase at Andertons Music Co. you may be asked if you want to opt in to leave a review with Google Customer Reviews. If you opt in we will share simple order and personal information with Google, solely for the purpose of leaving us a review.
  * **Feefo** \- are our customer reviews platform. At the point of purchase you will have the option to leave us a review based on your experience with Andertons Music Co. This means your personal information will be shared with Feefo, solely for the purpose of leaving us a review. This falls under the heading of market research. Collecting feedback and reviews, demonstrates how our customers have rated their experience, and so forms a normal and crucial part of the experience. Feedback is a way for Andertons Music Co. to understand how we can improve customer service and provide better marketing communications in the future. To read Feefo’s privacy policy, [click here.](https://www.feefo.com/business/gb_en/privacy-policy)
  * **DPD & UPS** \- To complete your online transactions, we will send the required details to our courier partners. This will include, but is not limited to: Name, Address, Phone Number, Email Address
  * **Westlake IT** \- As our trusted IT company, Westlake have remote access to our company servers.
  * **Fresh Relevance** \- our recommendations partner to help show product recommendations we think you will really like.
  * **Zendesk** \- Zendesk is a tool for managing and replying to customer enquiries. When you contact us using email or live chat your contact information will be stored in Zendesk.

**6\. Opting out of marketing**

We offer the opportunity to opt-out of marketing activities such as our email newsletters and postal mailings, and will not pass your data on to third-party companies. Look for the ‘unsubscribe' link at the bottom of each email, or contact us to opt out of other marketing formats.

**7\. Commitment to Data Security**

Your data is held in accordance with our data protection registration notification. When you place an order on this website, we consider the information you enter as private. The information is kept on a secure server protected from outside parties.

For your protection, we're also registered under the Data Protection Act 1998 and have given all appropriate notifications to the Information Commissioner.

We keep all your personally identifiable information secure. Only authorised employees, agents and contractors (who have agreed to keep information secure and confidential) have access to this information. All email newsletters from Andertons Music Co. offer automated unsubscribe services so you can opt out of further mailings. To opt out of any other form of marketing, please contact us.

**8\. Leaving This Website**

Our website may contain links to enable you to visit other websites of interest easily. However, once you have used these links to leave our site you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

Having said this, we abide by this privacy policy to the greatest extent we can in the management of external web services utilised by Andertons Music Co. such as Facebook, Youtube and Twitter. These services are however governed by their own privacy policies.

**9\. Additions**

From time to time these practices may change, usually when we introduce new technology to further enhance your shopping experience or our site performance but any changes will be listed below this 'Additions' section and will only be applied moving forwards.

**10\. General Data Protection Regulation (Added - 09/04/2018)**

In May 2018, a new EU regulation comes into force - The General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Simply put, GDPR raises the standards by which data privacy is measured. Andertons Music Co. takes your privacy very seriously and as such makes every effort to abide by the new rulings of GDPR. We will never contact you for marketing purposes without your express permission. The terms of this privacy policy have also been rearranged to make them as clear and transparent as possible.

**11\. Location Services (Added - 01/06/2019)**

Our trusted partner DB-IP enables us to provide more relevant delivery information around the site based on your IP address. No connection is made between your IP Address and your PII. This service is solely used to provide a more tailored experience on the site.
